Very artistic.
Très artistique.
We can put cement in between…
Nous pouvons mettre du ciment entre les deux.
Ji, Shri Mataji.
Ji, Shri Mataji.
Pizza? Pizza, yes.
Pizza? Des pizzas, oui.
[In Hindi: to make Pizza …
[En hindi: pour faire de la pizza.
I really liked it]
J'ai beaucoup aimé]
I purchased it a long time back.
Je l'ai acheté il y a longtemps.
Ji [yes].
Ji [oui].
You have a very, very good eye Shri Mataji, for beautiful places.
Vous avez un très, très bon œil Shri Mataji, pour les beaux endroits.
[In Hindi, let's go. It is very good for children]
[En hindi, allons-y. C'est très bien pour les enfants]
Ah, beautiful. And all this is with, with land it's with it.
Ah, magnifique. Et tout ça c'est avec, ce terrain va avec.
For about twenty metres is our land, twenty  meters.
Sur environ vingt mètres, c'est notre terrain, sur vingt mètres.
Twenty metres is our land.
Sur vingt mètres, c'est notre terrain.
I see.
Je vois.
Twenty metres, that’s a lot.
Vingt mètres, c'est beaucoup.
[In Hindi,  Romal felt very nice]
[En hindi, Romal se sentait très bien.]
Beautiful, very Beautiful.
C'est beau, très beau.
What else, what river is that?
Quoi d'autre, quelle rivière est-ce?
It's the Borbera.
C'est la Borbera.
Borbera is here?
La Borbera est là?
Yes.
Oui.
Very nice, absolutely beautiful.
Très joli, absolument magnifique.
Beautiful for children!
C'est magnifique pour les enfants.
Oh! Beautiful!
Oh! C'est beau!
This is the dining room Shri Mataji.
C'est la salle à manger Shri Mataji.
This is where children eat, here.
C'est ici que les enfants mangent.
And it's the Kitchen.
Et voilà la cuisine.
Kitchen Shri Mataji, kitchen.
La cuisine, Shri Mataji, la cuisine.
It's all very new?
Tout est neuf?
Yes.
Oui.
Oh, my God!
Oh mon Dieu!
[In Hindi, the kitchen is nice.]
[En hindi, la cuisine est agréable.]
Very good!
Très bon!
[In Hindi, very nice.]
[En hindi, très bien.]
Excellent.
Excellent.
[In Hindi,  this one is a Kitchen.]
[En hindi, celle-ci, c'est une cuisine.]
This one.
Celle-ci.
Sadhana is happy.
Sadhana est contente.
Very nice.
Très agréable.
They maintained it very well. Poor damage.
Ils l'ont très bien entretenu. Peu de dégâts.
[In Hindi, these are all the things of school.]
[En hindi, ce sont toutes les choses de l'école.]
[In Hindi, very good.]
[En hindi, très bien.]
[In Hindi, there is no mess in it.]
[En hindi, il n'y a pas de gâchis.]
From her, she's already there.
Pour elle, elle est déjà là.
I don’t know how many years back I have bought it.
Je ne sais pas depuis combien d'années je l'ai achetée.
I think it was in 95 or something like this. Long time back.
Je pense que c'était en 1995 ou quelque chose comme ça. Depuis longtemps.
[In Hindi, twelve, thirteen years ago.]
[En hindi, il y a douze, treize ans.]
[In Hindi, twelve years. Now see, this is very nice.]
[En hindi, douze ans. Maintenant, voyez, c'est très bien.]
Storeroom, for the food we get a big fridge. All things.
Le celier, pour la nourriture, nous avons un grand réfrigérateur. Toutes les choses
Storeroom and very big fridge.
Le celier et un très grand réfrigérateur.
[In Hindi, all things are very beautifully arranged.]
[En Hindi, toutes les choses sont très joliment arrangées.]
Very well arranged, very nice house.
C'est une maison très bien agencée, très agréable.
How many tables?
Combien il y a de tables?
[Hindi]
[Hindi]
How can you go upstairs?
Comment peut-on monter à l'étage?
We can go outside and we go up the ramp.
On peut sortir et on monte avec la rampe.
And we can go up, there's a [inaudible]. We take up around.
Et on peut monter, il y a un [inaudible]. Nous tournons autour.
There's a way, Shri Mataji, yes.
Il y a un moyen, Shri Mataji, oui.
[In Hindi, Ok. Let’s go.]
[En hindi, d'accord. Allons-y.]
We can get for small children?
Nous pouvons en obtenir pour les petits enfants?
Of course, Mother.
Bien sûr, Mère.
It’s better to get lower things and small thing and again this there.
Il vaut mieux avoir des choses plus basses et plus petites choses, et encore ceci là.
Ji, Shri Mataji.
Ji, Shri Mataji.
Lobby?
Le vestibule?
Laundry, laundry.
Une buanderie, une buanderie.
[In Hindi, purchased. Earlier it was not there. Now it has been put.]
[En hindi, c'est acheté. Auparavant, il n'y en avait pas. Maintenant, on l'a mis.]
This is new, new.
C'est neuf, neuf.
[In Hindi, washing machine. It’s new.]
[En hindi, une machine à laver. C'est neuf.]
Wah!
Wah!
They will have to take for the small children.
Ils devront en avoir pour les petits enfants.
This is the garden.
Voici le jardin.
Let me see.
Laissez-moi voir.
Beyond the tree, after the fence, there is a big space for meditation.
Au-delà de l'arbre, après la clôture, il y a un grand espace de méditation.
It's a nice, big area with many trees. And then there is a river.
C'est un bel et grand espace avec beaucoup d'arbres. Et puis il y a une rivière.
All that is our land.
Tout cela, c'est notre terrain.
Yes.
Oui.
So, we have a big, after the trees, we have a big area for meditation.
Donc, nous avons un grand, après les arbres, nous avons un grand espace pour la méditation.
And then we have a river.
Et puis nous avons une rivière.
And how many rooms upstairs?
Et combien de pièces à l'étage?
We have four, well there're two storeys. Two storeys.
Nous en avons quatre, eh bien, il y a deux étages. Deux étages.
And the top storey, we have bedrooms and we have four very big dormitories.
Et au dernier étage, nous avons des chambres et nous avons quatre très grands dortoirs.
[In Hindi, this kind of house I have never seen. From here we will start a compound.]
[En hindi, ce genre de maison, je n'en ai jamais vu. De là, nous allons commencer un vaste espace.]
Ji.
Ji.
For the children room.
Pour la chambre des enfants.
Yes. Yes, Shri Mataji.
Oui. Oui, Shri Mataji.
Or we can towards this.
Ou nous pouvons vers cela.
Yes, yes.
Oui, oui.
The first [inaudible] is the top floor.
Le premier [inaudible] est le dernier étage.
We can [inaudible] this.
Nous pouvons [inaudible] ceci.
This is garage, the garage for the car.
C'est le garage, le garage pour la voiture.
We'll have to bring the children in a lorry.
Nous devrons amener les enfants dans un camion.
Yes, Shri Mataji. In a bus.
Oui, Shri Mataji. Dans un bus.
A bus.
Un autobus.
Yes.
Oui.
This works?
Cela marche?
No, Shri Mataji, this is just - no, only flowers.
Non, Shri Mataji, c'est juste - non, c'est seulement des fleurs.
It's not a fountain.
Ce n'est pas une fontaine.
But we can make it work.
Mais nous pouvons la faire fonctionner.
Yes, yes, of course.
Oui, oui, biensûr.
Oh my God! This is the drawing-room?
Oh mon Dieu! C'est le salon?
Yes, Shri Mataji.
Oui, Shri Mataji.
And what is this small room?
Et quelle est cette petite pièce?
Bedroom.
Une chambre.
This is a mediation room, a meditation room for children.
C'est une salle de médiation, une salle de méditation pour les enfants.
What?
Quoi?
The children will meditate here and in the morning, they will come and meditate here.
Les enfants méditeront ici et le matin, ils viendront méditer ici.
[Inaudible]
[Inaudible]
Yes. It’s very strong.
Oui. C'est très fort.
Very.
Très.
And what about this here?
Et qu'en est-il de cela ici?
Same.
Pareil.
Same?
Pareil?
Yes.
Oui.
Beautiful surrounding, beautiful, very good.
C'st un beau cadre, beau, très bien.
You can’t take a more beautiful nature.
Vous ne pourriez pas avoir une plus belle nature.
[In Hindi, this needs to be closed here.]
[En hindi, ceci a besoin d'être clos ici.]
Ji.
Ji.
[In Hindi, small kids will be there, won’t they?]
[En hindi, il y aura des petits, n'est-ce pas?]
They will be from five years, five, six years, there is no need.
Il y en aura à partir de cinq ans, cinq, six ans, ce n'est pas nécessaire.
From 6 years, Shri Mataji.
A partir de 6 ans, Shri Mataji.
[In Hindi, see, how beautiful are the fruits.]
[En hindi, voyez, comme les fruits sont beaux.]
Well safe, well safe, they don’t climb on the top.
C'est sécurisé, sécurisé, ils ne grimpent pas par-dessus.
No.
Non.
Well maintained.
C'est bien entretenu.
This is kitchen.
C'est la cuisine.
It's a small kitchen, small kitchen.
C'est une petite cuisine, une petite cuisine.
Just for tea, coffee.
Juste pour le thé, le café.
That one.
Celle-ci.
Yes, this one.
Oui, celle-ci.
Kitchen.
Une cuisine.
This is bedroom.
C'est une chambre.
Ji.
Ji.
Whose Bedroom? Not for children.
La chambre de qui? Pas pour les enfants.
Aunties.
Pour les tatass.
Aunties' bedroom.
La chambre des tatas.
Only for the teachers.
Uniquement pour les enseignants.
Ji, Shri Mataji.
Ji, Shri Mataji.
Twelve, very good.
Douze, très bien.
You know, for boys who are staying nearby, we'll have a bus.
Vous savez, pour les garçons qui habitent à proximité, nous aurons un bus.
How many can be here?
Combien peuvent rester ici?
We can have forty children easily.
On peut avoir quarante enfants, facilement.
And where do they study?
Et où étudient-ils?
Downstairs, in the dining hall, they can study.
En bas, dans la salle à manger, ils peuvent étudier.
And they will go to the local school.
Et ils iront à l'école locale.
Ah, the school. The school is the local school.
Ah, l'école. L'école est l'école locale.
They go in the bus to the local school
Ils vont en bus à l'école locale
and they will come here for their homework,
et ils viendront ici pour leurs devoirs,
for their sleeping, for their playing, for their sports.
pour le coucher, pour le jeu, pour les sport.
Where is the dining room?
Où est la salle à manger?
Downstairs, Shri Mataji.
En bas, Shri Mataji.
Oh, downstairs.
Oh, en bas.
Forty.
Quarante.
Forty, yes. I think forty is very comfortable.
Quarante, oui. Je pense que quarante, c'est très confortable.
Very nice.
Très agréable.
Look at these!
Regarde-les!
Beautiful. Congratulations!
C'est beau. Toutes nos félicitations!
Thank you.
Merci.
Thank you Shri Mataji! Thank you.
Merci Shri Mataji! Merci.
Very clean, very cleanly kept.
Très propre, très proprement tenu.
So, how many beds now?
Alors, combien de lits maintenant?
We have, I think, forty beds.
Nous avons, je pense, quarante lits.
Forty.
Quarante.
Forty beds.
Quarante lits.
[In Hindi, how did you like Sadhana?]
[En hindi, comment as-tu aimé Sadhana?]
[In Hindi, very beautiful Ma. Amazing! Wonderful!]
[En hindi, c'est très beau Ma. Incroyable! Merveilleux!]
I have to get small tables and chairs.
Je dois me procurer des petites tables et des chaises.
Yes, you are.
Oui, vous le ferez.
Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji.
Hello! May God bless you!
Bonjour! Que Dieu te bénisse!
Thank you Shri Mataji.
Merci, Shri Mataji.
I was just now thinking about you.
Je pensais à toi à l'instant.
What a beautiful house!
Quelle belle maison!
Do you like the new arrangement?
Aimez-vous le nouvel arrangement?
Wonderful!
Merveilleux!
We arrange the-
Nous organisons le-
Very good for children.
c'est très bien pour les enfants.
We spent many money but now the house for the children is very beautiful.
Nous avons dépensé beaucoup d'argent mais maintenant la maison, pour les enfants, est très belle.
Perfect, perfect. Not to use it would be a crime.
Parfait, parfait. Ne pas l'utiliser serait un crime.
[In Hindi]
[En hindi]
Anyway teacher, she wants the school to come.
De toute façon professeur, elle veut que l'école vienne.
No, no, the important is to start it then we can manage it.
Non, non, l'important c'est de le démarrer, puis on peut le gérer.
What we can do is to have one Italian there.
Ce que nous pouvons faire, c'est avoir de l'italien là-bas.
But I want to start English here
Mais je veux commencer avec l'anglais ici,
to prepare them to go to other school.
pour les préparer à aller dans une autre école.
To go to Daglio?
Pour aller à Daglio?
This here is, these are the toilettes for the girls.
Voilà, ce sont les toilettes des filles.
This is for boys.
C'est pour les garçons.
Ah, so you have two sets.
Ah, donc vous avez deux toilettes.
Yes.
Oui.
[In Hindi]
[En hindi]
This is the regulation of the school.
C'est le règlement de l'école.
Yes, you're with it.
Oui, vous le resectez.
[Inaudible] for children. All these chairs and all that,
[Inaudible] pour les enfants. Toutes ces chaises et tout ça,
for small, for small, chairs and all.
pour les petits, pour les petits, les chaises et tout.
We will buy small chairs and tables.
Nous achèterons des petites chaises et des tables.
So, how many tables and small chairs you should buy now.
Alors, [voyez] maintenantvcombien de tables et de petites chaises vous devriez acheter.
Yes, Shri Mataji, I'll tell them.
Oui, Shri Mataji, je vais leur dire.
And how many tables.
Et combien de tables.
Yes. Yes, Shri Mataji.
Oui. Oui, Shri Mataji.
Because they'll be small.
Parce qu'ils seront petits.
Up to five years, they'll come [short name for Sadhana]?
Jusqu'à cinq ans, ils viendront [petit nom de Sadhana]?
Five years, six, seven.
Cinq ans, six, sept.
Six to eleven.
De six à onze ans.
That's why. So, we can get other chairs.
C'est pourquoi. Ainsi, nous pouvons obtenir d'autres chaises.
O, I just purchase this, that's all.
Oh, je viens d'acheter ça, c'est tout.
Our desire is to fulfil your, your desires and your will.
Notre désir est de réaliser vos, vos désirs et votre volonté.
This was my old idea to bring them to England because tthey want to learn English.
C'était ma vieille idée de les amener en Angleterre parce qu'ils veulent apprendre l'anglais.
And now we'll go and see the other big school library.
Et maintenant, nous allons aller voir l'autre grande bibliothèque de l'école.
See, you can make another bedroom here.
Vous voyez, vous pouvez faire une autre chambre ici.
So that two and two four.
Alors deux, et deux quatre.
[In Hindi]
[En hindi]
That time I use to walk when I saw this.
A ce moment-là, je marchais quand j'ai vu ça.
Amazing. Amazing. Amazing is the word. Amazing.
Incroyable. Incroyable. Incroyable, c'est le mot. Incroyable.
We are so lucky, Shri Mataji, to have you as our Mother.
Nous avons tellement de chance, Shri Mataji, de vous avoir comme Mère.
You look after us so well. We are so lucky.
Vous vous occuoez si bien de nous. Nous sommes tellement chanceux.
But I, I didn’t understand that, "Why people didn't buy this?"
Mais moi, je n'ai pas compris pourquoi les gens n'ont pas acheté ça.
I couldn’t understand. Because it is an institution, I think.
Je n'ai pas compris. Parce que c'est une institution, je pense.
I think the house was waiting for you.
Je pense que la maison vous attendait.
[Laughter] it must be.
[Rires] Ça doit être ça.
No, I just asked, so I bought it.
Non, j'ai juste démandé ensuite je l'ai achetée.
No, in any case, you can put bars there.
Non, dans tous les cas, vous pouvez mettre y des barreaux.
Yes.
Oui.
First, the decor, this is so beautiful.
Tout d'abord, le décor, c'est tellement beau.
This is made in this country?
C'est fait dans ce pays?
Yes, Shri Mataji.
Oui, Shri Mataji.
Really good.
Très bien.
They make beautiful things.
Ils font de belles choses.
Marvellous place, beautiful style.
C'est un endroit merveilleux, un beau style.
[In Hindi, let's go]
[En hindi, allons-y]